<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>UNREALENGINE on Empires</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/tags/unrealengine/</link><description>Recent content in UNREALENGINE on Empires</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.empiresmod.com/tags/unrealengine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress Report, July 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-focus-and-projectiles"&gt;Project Focus and Projectiles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of July was spent trying to network the ECS projectiles. We got pretty far, creating a network transport layer and defining the base protocol to replicate bullets, but we got bogged down packaging the bullets and sending them across the wire to remote clients. After a few weeks of fighting with the Engine, late in July we decided to shelve ECS bullets for now, and approach it again when the project is further along. We have a working projectile system, so it would be best to focus our efforts on things that don’t exist, like Vehicles and Buildings. Also, Mayama creating a ton of amazing vehicles helped us realize we needed to start getting them in game sooner rather than later.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress Report, June 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="vehicle-models"&gt;Vehicle Models&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h6 id="mayama"&gt;Mayama&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to make all the remaining NF vehicle models. As always, no micro details like rivets &amp;amp; bolts and stuff, I add that when we are 100% sure that we do not alter the model in any way. Oh and suspension + steering this time because, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, it looks kinda dump without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2021/images/image9.png" alt="alt_text" title="image_tooltip"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new NF Jeep. I tried to make something somewhere between a realistic military buggy and mad max (without the spikes). It&amp;rsquo;s bigger than the source Empires jeep but if you want to make something that&amp;rsquo;s more than a box with 4 wheels you need more space.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, May 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="unreal-engine-5"&gt;Unreal Engine 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h6 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unreal Engine 5 came out this month, surprising just about everyone. Initial observations show that it’s as monumental of a leap forward as Epic was promising, which is a good sign. I spent some time this month evaluating the new features in UE5 and what kind of work it would take to port what we’ve done with Empires in UE4 to UE5. The short answer is: not a whole lot of work needed, and we could port soon if we wanted. The most significant changes in UE5 were to the rendering pipeline, and it’s a part of the engine we have not touched at all. Because we’ve made no customizations or changes there, all of our content can port trivially to UE5. The Gameplay Framework has changed, but the current UE4 framework still exists, which means we can just use the UE4-style code until we port over to the new modular features.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, April 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-april-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-april-2021/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h6 id="royawesome"&gt;RoyAwesome&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone. It’s been a while since our last update. My bad. I kinda out for a few months between this project and work, and a healthy amount of seasonal depression, and Empires fell to the wayside. Progress didn’t really stop, we just kind of stopped writing updates. Given the all-volunteer nature of our team, this is pretty expected, and my major focus right now is to prevent the project from stalling if I or others burn out.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, November 2020</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-november-2020/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project is humming along nicely! After a brief slowdown back in September, we’ve made huge amounts of progress in November, and even hit a major game development milestone… Empires UE4 is playable from start to finish! That’s right, you can hop into a game, play it, and then once a victory condition is achieved, the match ends and the server goes to the next map.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building the game loop was a huge part of the current milestone, and we are in the final stretch of closing out Milestone 2. To recap what Milestone 2 contains:&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Squads and Weapons Progress</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-september-october-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-september-october-2020/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey everyone! Combined update for September and October this month. Due to the nature of the all-volunteer team and a number of us having day jobs, we ran into some issues getting an update out last month. However, progress continues and we’ve had a lot of discussion for the post 1.0 future of this project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are working on a new website, one that will allow us to post updates more frequently and support the growing project (and maybe finally fix https too). It’s in progress and we hope to have it done in the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chat, Recoil, and Weapons</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-august-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-august-2020/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Everyone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month I have the absolute pleasure to announce that we have completed the first development milestone for the Empires UE4 project. This milestone completion is a major achievement for this team, and is now the furthest any Empires remake has ever gotten in nearly 15 years. While we have quite a ways to go until this project is playable and fun, I am very proud of this team and the progress they have made in these last 3 short months.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Glycen City and Players</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hey Everyone! Another month in the bag for UE4 and we’ve really kicked some butt. We achieved a major milestone this month, we have held &lt;strong&gt;multiple&lt;/strong&gt; playtests! That’s right, we’ve started to be able to play the game and get a general gameplay loop going. We even found a crash while testing!&lt;/p&gt;












&lt;a href="https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/img1.jpg" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/img1_hu_8ccb806c444418ae.jpg" width="1280" height="720"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
 &lt;source src="https://cdn.discordapp.com/attachments/698655659193008208/734615702643671070/2020-07-19_20-37-32.mp4" type="video/mp4"&gt;
 Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This is a large milestone because it has a feeling of making this project real. It’s also the furthest along that any Empires remakes has ever gotten, so we are pretty happy about that.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Music and Damage Progress</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2020/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="project-update"&gt;Project Update&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="roy-awesome"&gt;Roy Awesome&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second full month is complete working on the Empires UE4 port. We have made some very appreciable progress toward completing the Minimum Viable milestone, and we will soon be able to check that one off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June was a bit slower than May, mostly due to many of our team members returning to work and the reality of life during COVID settling in. As a volunteer, free time project, we are at the whims of real life obligations to make progress, and while this month’s update is shorter than last, we still made an insane amount of progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unreal Port - The Intro</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2020/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hello Everyone! I am incredibly excited to announce that we are porting Empires to the Unreal Engine! This project has been going on for the better part of the month, and we are making extremely good progress. We have brought together a great team and while we are only working nights and weekends on this project, I hope that you can all see how fast we are progressing and how exciting it is for Empires to have a future on a game engine that lets the game excel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>