<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Empires</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/</link><description>Recent content on Empires</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.empiresmod.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Empires Mod 2.38.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-38-0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-38-0/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.38.0 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Replaced vehicle shell particle effects with the new particle systems. Each cannon can (and now does) have a different trail of particles. This may make it easier to identify the locations of artillery tanks, and notice incoming artillery shells. Large rework of the vehicle heat mechanics Added a fourth &amp;ldquo;Overheat&amp;rdquo; heat region. Now there is &amp;ldquo;Low&amp;rdquo; (Green), &amp;ldquo;Medium&amp;rdquo; (Yellow), &amp;ldquo;High&amp;rdquo; (Orange), and &amp;ldquo;Overheat&amp;rdquo; (Red) The portion of the heat bar that is not filled will still be displayed, but in a way more muted color.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.37.4 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.37.4 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bugfixes Fixed a problem where upgradable buildings were not precaching their models correctly, resulting in invisible models when placing the building for the first time. Script/Game Balance Research Advanced Chassis Increased Cost from 750 to 900 Increased Time from 250 to 300 Heavy Tank Chassis Increased Cost from 750 to 1000 Increased Time from 150 to 200 Infantry Resistances Scout Reduced Explosion Bonus Resistance from 10% to 5%.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.37.3 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.37.3 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bugfixes Fixed a bug preventing explosion damage from being blocked correctly. Fixed a bug that would allow one too many players to join a team before being classed as unbalanced when using mp_teams_unbalance_limit. Script/Game Balance Research Capacitive Armor Increased the research cost from 240 to 360 Increased the research time from 60 to 90 Reduced Cost of APC Chassis research from 360 to 240 Reduced Time of APC Chassis research from 90 to 60 Vehicle Armors Capacitive Armor Increased the weight from 13 to 15 Reactive Reduced Health from 120 to 110 Infantry Weapons SMG1 Increased Clip Size from 30 to 35 Increased number of clips from 3 to 4 SMG2 Increased Clip Size from 35 to 40 Increased Engineer&amp;rsquo;s number of clips from 3 to 4 Increased Scout&amp;rsquo;s number of clips from 4 to 5</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.37.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.37.2 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bugfixes Fixed a few bugs caused by a large refactor of the game&amp;rsquo;s codebase: Fixed a bug with ML turret targeting. Fixed a bug with wall preview models not being visible. Removed a left over debug statement from vehicle code. (Console would spam &amp;ldquo;WL_WAIST&amp;rdquo; if vehicle was partially submerged in water) Script/Game Balance Research AFV and LT are now set to be researched at the start of the game (Start_Researched 1).</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.37.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.37.1 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added the recycleGivesRefund (&amp;ldquo;Give Refund on Recycle?&amp;rdquo; in Hammer) parameter for building entities. If set to 1 (the default), then when the building is recycled the resources are refunded. If set to 0, then when the building is recycled, no resources are given to the team. The commander will get feedback for what the refund cost will be when triggering a recycle on a building.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.37.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-37-0/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.37.0 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Grenades and mines make sounds when they bounce against surfaces. Added armor impact sounds. Distinct sounds play when a vehicle&amp;rsquo;s armor is damaged, a vehicle&amp;rsquo;s hull is damaged, and when a sticky grenade latches to a tank hull. Different armors can have different sounds, though most armors currently do not. Enabled several unused NF taunts.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.36.3 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.36.3 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Potential fix for the player collision issues introduced in 2.36.0 Script/Game Balance Vehicle Chassis Northern Faction Heavy Tank Increased available weight by 60 Brenodi Empire Heavy Tank Increased available weight by 60 Vehicle Weapons Biological Cannon Reduced Weight from 120 to 100 Homing Missile Reduced Lock On Time from 0.5 to 0.4 Reduced Lock On Range Modifier from 0.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.36.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.36.2 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a few issues caused by changes in 2.36.0 Fixed player round stats not restoring if the player reconnected to the server. Fixed issues with collision of projectiles/players. Fixed an issue causing soundscape entities to not play any sounds. Script/Game Balance Research Biological Cannon Increased Cost from 360 to 480 Increased Time from 90 to 120 Vehicle Weapons Biological Missile Reduced Cycle time from 3 to 1.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.36.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.36.1 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed commander vote issues introduced in the last update. Fixed a client crash. Other changes Changed the colour of the border indicating empty armour plates on the vehicle HUD. These are now dark red instead of grey. Modified soft flesh impact sounds slightly.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.36.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-36-0/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.36.0 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added angle snapping to commander building placement. This shares a key bind with multi-unit selection. (Default key is shift.) Added firing sounds to MG turrets. The vehicle health HUD has been improved: The health of each armor plate and hull are overlaid as a number. This feature can be enabled in the advanced options section.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.35.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-35-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-35-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.35.1 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed an issue causing Sourcemod plugins to malfunction on Linux servers. Fixed a divide-by-zero bug in emp_engineer_map_brush / emp_engineer_map_object entities&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;raise on build&amp;rdquo; functionality. This was causing entities to not spawn in correctly. In some cases where these entities were parented to other entities, it would crash the server. Fixed a few issues with how scout hide is applied to players.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.35.0 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-35-0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-35-0/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.35.0 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added a screen overlay that is applied when players are afflicted with the damage over time effect of biological weapons. Added tips to the loading screen. (Similar to when the game was on the 2007 version of the engine) Changed the old scout hide screen darkening to use a screen overlay that is essentially a vignette effect instead of darkening the whole screen.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.9 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-9/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-9/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.9 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Double clicking of weapons/armor/engine in vehicle customization now adds/removes. Armor and engine will swap what is equipped if trying to add a different armor. Bug fixes Fixed a bug causing engineer tool to lose charge if the player triggered a re-equip before deploying the weapon. Fixed a bug preventing vehicles from repairing on repair stations when taking DMG_CRUSH damage type.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.8 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-8/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.8 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Changes to squad menu Fixed some alignment issues on text / icons. Text should is now set as &amp;lsquo;proportional&amp;rsquo; and should better based on resolution. Health values update more reliably and are now colored Red-&amp;gt;Green based on health percentage. (Squad aura indicator is now white, to avoid confusion.) The Squad Power icon now has text displaying time left on it&amp;rsquo;s timer.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.7 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-7/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.7 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug causing the engineer tool to regain more ammo than expected when re-applying the player&amp;rsquo;s class. Fixed an issue preventing map spawned ammo crates from re-supplying tanks in certain situations. Fixed a problem with the squad artillery ability being activated in areas that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed. (Non sky-box.) Script/Game Balance Infantry Resists RPG Resistances and resulting Damage to Infantry is now same as Mortar Scout Increased RPG Resist from 0 to 0.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.6 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-6/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.6 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fix order distances having incorrect unit conversion from inches to meters. Fix an exploit allowing players to refill their engineer tool to full when changing class. Disable mine detonation for players on ladders. Remove double averaging of scoreboard latency, engine code already handles it. Script/Game Balance Infantry Resists Engineer &amp;amp; Rifleman Increased Mortar Resist from 0 to 0.</description></item><item><title>Introducing emp_cargo, a map by community member Oktay</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/emp_cargo-community-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/emp_cargo-community-post/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re pleased to announce the release of a new map, made by community member Oktay
This beautiful commander map has 4 different sections which open up based on the player count. It has zip lines, strong rivers, elevators (also with lava underneath) and tons of shipping containers!
You can check out some previews of the map below:
Briefing Brenodi Empire:
The Northern Faction is attacking our port which support our military supplies in this ongoing war.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.5 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-5/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.5 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug/exploit that was allowing refineries to be placed at no resource cost. Fixed a bug where the engineer tool kit would not recharge the correct amount if you changed your skills while it was holstered. Fixed the &amp;ldquo;Just in time&amp;rdquo; achievement being awarded to the local player even if it was a different player that triggered the achievement.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.4 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.4 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
General changes Increased all voice line sound attenuation distance by about 1000 units. Removed unnecessary binary files from server packages. (Some client files were being shipped to server packages unnecessarily.) Added server commands to limit bunny hopping velocity gain and to enable auto bunny hopping, both are disabled by default. sv_enablebunnyhopping &amp;amp; sv_autobunnyhopping Bug fixes Fixed a server crash relating to mines not being removed correctly.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.3 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.3 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added a squad member ID to both the mini-map and the Squad HUD. This can be used to locate specific players. Added player requests to the squad HUD. (Ammo/Health/Repairs) Added an indicator in the Squad HUD for players receiving the squad aura effect. (Green box next to player health when player is receiving the benefit of the squad aura.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.2 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a code typo which was causing a bug with explosion damage, meaning double damage could occur to vehicles. Fixed a few issues relating to checking a player&amp;rsquo;s team for displaying icons on the minimap. Sometimes player icons wouldn&amp;rsquo;t display even though they should. Fixed building smoke not calling StopEmission if the particle system is in a sleep state.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.34.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-34-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.34.1 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added cvar &amp;ldquo;emp_sv_drop_cooked_grenades&amp;rdquo;, this is disabled by default until some gameplay testing can be conducted and feedback gathered. Causes grenades to drop when players die if they had already pulled the pin out. (Excluding mines) Bug fixes Fixed an issue with e-repair preventing mines from being defused inside a damaged friendly building. Fixed an issue that was preventing wall gibs from spawning when destroyed.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.33.5 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-5/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-5/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.33.5 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug with artillery feedback only showing once if your shell/missile hit the exact same place. Potentially fixed a bug causing walls to be forever stuck in the building carcass state; the wall would be invincible and never removed. This bug was incredibly hard to reproduce but it seemed that the bug was directly tied to the recycle function.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.33.4 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.33.4 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug causing the squad leader&amp;rsquo;s aura to not reset if all other members left the squad whilst being in the squad aura radius. Fixed a bug causing squad members to receive the squad aura effect even though their squad leader died. Fixed some issues with resource points becoming disabled in some situations where the refinery placement failed.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.33.3 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.33.3 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug on Linux servers which caused vehicles to be able to aim beyond the intended cannon pitch angle restrictions. (You could aim down inside your own tank and self-damage the tank) Fixed a bug involving tank cannon shells getting stuck floating in the air when colliding with the tank that fired it.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.33.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.33.2 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added resource point icons to the minimap. Resource output for each resource point can be seen on the full-sized map. Resource points on the full-sized map have a color coded glow surrounding them to depict importance. Yellow (Lowest output) -&amp;gt; Green (2nd lowest output) -&amp;gt; Cyan (2nd highest output) -&amp;gt; Fuchsia (Highest output) Bug fixes Fixed some problems with how entities are detected by commands issued using the F-Menu.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.33.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-33-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.33.1 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Implemented a system that checks which player body parts are blocked by other objects before applying explosion damage. Explosion damage and Bio DoT now scales based on the mass of the objects blocking each body part. (Bio Dot is only changed for explosions, Bio MG is unaffected) Each body part is checked separately and scales the damage for that part depending on the blocking object&amp;rsquo;s mass.</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress Report, July 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2021/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2021/</guid><description>Project Focus and Projectiles Roy Awesome Most of July was spent trying to network the ECS projectiles. We got pretty far, creating a network transport layer and defining the base protocol to replicate bullets, but we got bogged down packaging the bullets and sending them across the wire to remote clients. After a few weeks of fighting with the Engine, late in July we decided to shelve ECS bullets for now, and approach it again when the project is further along.</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress Report, June 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2021/</guid><description>Vehicle Models Mayama I managed to make all the remaining NF vehicle models. As always, no micro details like rivets &amp;amp; bolts and stuff, I add that when we are 100% sure that we do not alter the model in any way. Oh and suspension + steering this time because, let&amp;rsquo;s be honest, it looks kinda dump without it.
The new NF Jeep. I tried to make something somewhere between a realistic military buggy and mad max (without the spikes).</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, May 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2021/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2021/</guid><description>Unreal Engine 5 Roy Awesome Unreal Engine 5 came out this month, surprising just about everyone. Initial observations show that it’s as monumental of a leap forward as Epic was promising, which is a good sign. I spent some time this month evaluating the new features in UE5 and what kind of work it would take to port what we’ve done with Empires in UE4 to UE5. The short answer is: not a whole lot of work needed, and we could port soon if we wanted.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.32.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-32-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-32-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.32.2 is live on Steam.
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed an issue with how explosions determine if they were blocked by the world, this would sometimes false flag as being blocked by the world even if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. (Because the world entity is the fall-back entity for a missed entity-trace) Added the default mod_hl2 project&amp;rsquo;s detail.vbsp definitions with Empires specific definitions appended to the end of the file.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.32.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-32-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-32-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.32.1 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
General changes Added a 1 second delay after placement before walls can be recycled. Refactored Steam Rich Presence code to hopefully optimize things. Vehicle &amp;ldquo;Base weight&amp;rdquo; values have all been set to 0. This is so that the weight value shown in the menu&amp;rsquo;s is only displaying the current equipment weight and the total available weight.</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, April 2021</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-april-2021/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-april-2021/</guid><description>Project Update RoyAwesome Hey everyone. It’s been a while since our last update. My bad. I kinda out for a few months between this project and work, and a healthy amount of seasonal depression, and Empires fell to the wayside. Progress didn’t really stop, we just kind of stopped writing updates. Given the all-volunteer nature of our team, this is pretty expected, and my major focus right now is to prevent the project from stalling if I or others burn out.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.31.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-31-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-31-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.31.2 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Increased player icon fade distances 4000 units for revive, 3000 for everything else (ammo/health/squad icons). Also increased their scale very slightly as of last patch. Bug fixes Fixed a bug that would cause certain buildings to stop functioning after triggering it to recycle, then cancelling the recycle. (Turrets/Radar(Vehicle scanning function only, research capability was unaffected)) Fixed a visual bug with melee which would cause the dynamic crosshair to expand even though it didn&amp;rsquo;t increase bullet spread.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.31.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-31-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-31-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.31.1 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Player names and revive icons now follow ragdolls correctly rather than staying at the death location. Changed the revive icon to something simpler that is able to be re-colored in code and faded as to not block too much space on screen. Revive icon is now red for team mates and yellow for squad mates.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.9 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-9/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-9/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.9 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug causing localization to fail for vehicle kill-assist strings. Fixed a bug causing simple/critical kill-assists to record the wrong damage amount and potentially award the critical assist to the wrong player. Fixed a bug where player&amp;rsquo;s would get stuck in ammo/health crates spawned by capturing flags. Crates will now spawn when the spawn location is free from player obstruction.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.8 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-8/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-8/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.8 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Maps / Level design Moved all of the tool textures into the correct folder. (materials/common/tools -&amp;gt; materials/tools) The simple reason for this is that Empires was not overriding the HL2 textures, which causes duplicates to appear in the menus. Mappers will need to use the texture replace feature in hammer to point to the new location before compiling.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.7 (Hotfix) Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-7/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.7 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug with scout hide not being removed when using squad hide and certain weapons (engineer kit/RPG/Mortar) Fixed a bug with the squad aura icon displaying the wrong icon when changing between squads (Displayed for less than a second but it&amp;rsquo;s now fixed.) Fixed a bug preventing squad aura effect from being removed when leaving squads sometimes.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.6 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-6/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-6/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.6 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed an issue causing degreesSlow/degreesFast vehicle handling variables to be overridden by hard-coded values. (There shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be any issues caused by fixing this as script values have been adjusted to match) RPG now uses a different 3rd person reload animation as there was no RPG animation available. (Uses HL2&amp;rsquo;s AR2 reload as it is the closest visual fit) Fixed an issue with accuracy upgrade not using the script value when adjusting weapon base spread.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.5 (Hotfix) Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-5/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.5 (Hotfix) which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug causing infantry weapon spread decrement values to not be consistent. Sometimes the spread would decrease a lot more for no reason, this fix will be followed up by additional spread value changes in the scripts to address any balance changes that fixing this may have caused.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.4 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-4/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.4 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed some bugs relating to the recent additions to the tank cannon penetration checks (System that prevents firing when cannon is inside something other than vehicles/players) Fixed some mini-map icons appearing for the wrong team. (An example is being able to see the enemy squad leader icon in some circumstances) Fixed vehicle exits being able to be blocked by players on your team Fixed a bug with squad aura being applied to squad leaders 100% of the time Fixed various possible crashes relating to weapons (and 1 with wall placement) Fixed a networking issue causing the player icon on the mini-map not updating when swapping the revive skill on/off.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.3 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-3/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.3 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a bug where infantry weapon spread wasn&amp;rsquo;t decrementing when going to iron-sights. Fixed a bug with squad aura effects not being reapplied properly. (Most noticeable with squad accuracy upgrade as it wasn&amp;rsquo;t consistently being applied, using cl_dynamiccrosshair it appeared to cause spread to pulse) Fixed an issue where players would appear to be hovering when entering a vehicle while in mid air.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.2 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-2/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.2 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Bug fixes Fixed a rare crash that was caused by weapons Fixed a networking issue related to rotating the command view Fixed a bug causing spawns to appear blocked by team mates Fixed a bug that caused player movement to be slowed down when leaving the command vehicle Fixed an issue where players could be launched into the air by vehicles Players that get stuck inside enemy vehicles are now killed instead of attempting to apply force to get them out (Fixes roadkill not working 100% of the time) Player ragdolls now have some initial force applied to them when the player dies, previously the ragdoll would just fall to the ground.</description></item><item><title>Empires Mod 2.30.1 Released!</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/empiresmod-update-2-30-1/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce version 2.30.1 which is live on Steam right now!
Join us on Discord! https://discord.gg/UH6Sc6B
Changelog:
Features Added a new particle effect for turrets disabled by concussion grenades. Changes to how re-equip functions: Re-equip will now restore the previously active weapon, provided the player still has the same weapon. NOTE: Previously the active weapon would be changed to the weapon in slot 2 regardless of what the player was previously holding.</description></item><item><title>Empires UE4 Progress, November 2020</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-november-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-november-2020/</guid><description>Project Update The project is humming along nicely! After a brief slowdown back in September, we’ve made huge amounts of progress in November, and even hit a major game development milestone… Empires UE4 is playable from start to finish! That’s right, you can hop into a game, play it, and then once a victory condition is achieved, the match ends and the server goes to the next map.
Building the game loop was a huge part of the current milestone, and we are in the final stretch of closing out Milestone 2.</description></item><item><title>Squads and Weapons Progress</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-september-october-2020/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-september-october-2020/</guid><description>Project Update Roy Awesome Hey everyone! Combined update for September and October this month. Due to the nature of the all-volunteer team and a number of us having day jobs, we ran into some issues getting an update out last month. However, progress continues and we’ve had a lot of discussion for the post 1.0 future of this project.
We are working on a new website, one that will allow us to post updates more frequently and support the growing project (and maybe finally fix https too).</description></item><item><title>Chat, Recoil, and Weapons</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-august-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-august-2020/</guid><description>Project Update Roy Awesome Hey Everyone
This month I have the absolute pleasure to announce that we have completed the first development milestone for the Empires UE4 project. This milestone completion is a major achievement for this team, and is now the furthest any Empires remake has ever gotten in nearly 15 years. While we have quite a ways to go until this project is playable and fun, I am very proud of this team and the progress they have made in these last 3 short months.</description></item><item><title>Glycen City and Players</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-july-2020/</guid><description>Project Update Roy Awesome Hey Everyone! Another month in the bag for UE4 and we’ve really kicked some butt. We achieved a major milestone this month, we have held multiple playtests! That’s right, we’ve started to be able to play the game and get a general gameplay loop going. We even found a crash while testing!
Your browser does not support the video tag. This is a large milestone because it has a feeling of making this project real.</description></item><item><title>Music and Damage Progress</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2020/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-june-2020/</guid><description>Project Update Roy Awesome Our second full month is complete working on the Empires UE4 port. We have made some very appreciable progress toward completing the Minimum Viable milestone, and we will soon be able to check that one off.
June was a bit slower than May, mostly due to many of our team members returning to work and the reality of life during COVID settling in. As a volunteer, free time project, we are at the whims of real life obligations to make progress, and while this month’s update is shorter than last, we still made an insane amount of progress.</description></item><item><title>Unreal Port - The Intro</title><link>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2020/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.empiresmod.com/posts/unreal-progress-report-may-2020/</guid><description>Hello Everyone! I am incredibly excited to announce that we are porting Empires to the Unreal Engine! This project has been going on for the better part of the month, and we are making extremely good progress. We have brought together a great team and while we are only working nights and weekends on this project, I hope that you can all see how fast we are progressing and how exciting it is for Empires to have a future on a game engine that lets the game excel.</description></item></channel></rss>